



Nikita Rajpurohit

Mobile No:- +91 9764044304

Email ID :- nikita-deepak.rajpurohit@capgemini.com

Professional Summary

A big data developer with over 1 year of experience in SQL, Big data, and Python. I have knowledge of Hadoop, Linux and PySpark as well. A team player seeking a beginner role to develop and maintain big data solutions, data management systems for organization.

Skills Profile

Technical

T C STITTE CT		
Operating System	Windows , Linux(Basics)	
Environment	MySQL Server, Jupyter, Notebook Eclipse IDE	
Database	MySQL , Oracle, SQL Server	
Internet Tools	MySQL, Oracle, MS Word	
Languages	SQL, C, Python (Basics), Unix	
Other	Big data	

Functional

Management and Leadership Skills	Team Member, Decision making skills
Training & Development	Trained in Big data technologies



Professional Experience

Duplicate Resume detection

01/2023-05/2023

Role - Developer/team member

Description- Build a system to detect data matching percentage of two resumes from the dataset using Python at backend. Used data visualization techniques to represent the data clearly for better understanding at user end.

System for Hospital Management

02/2022 - 02/2022

2017 2021

Role - Developer/team member

Description - The system is build for Hospital Management which requires a big data system to resolve some of their queries for the growth of the business. Using this system they can analyze the total income,profits,improvements to be taken by running some querires for example total income for hospital in this year or specific patient's details and more such related queries which will help hospital management in beneficial way.

System For Music Entertainment Company

10/2021 - 11/2021

Role- Developer/Team member

Description-The system is build for Music Entertainment Company which requires a big data system to resolve some of their queries for the growth of the business. Using this system they can analyze the business growth by running some querires for example in which region business is doing good or what type of videos have maximum views and more such related queries. The System is build with the help of MySQL and Hive. The tables in data wareshouse database satisfies all the business queries of the music entertainment company.

Certifications

Big Data Foundation Certification by Degreed SQL for Data Science Certification by Coursera Hacker Rank SQL Certification
Basic Python Certification by Udemy
Python basics certification by Degreed
Data analysis using PySpark by Coursera
Hands on Python by Coursera
PySpark Fundamentals by Degreed

Education

HC Dograd

DKTE Society's Textile and Engineering Institute Ichalkaranji, Maharashtra, India, Bachelor of Technology in E&TC	2017 - 2021
Higher Secondary Education /12 th -	2016 – 2017

Sanjay Ghodawat Institute Sangli, Maharashtra, India, Higher Secondary Education

Secondary Education / 10th - 2014 – 2015

The Adarsh Shikshan Mandir Miraj, Maharashtra, India, Secondary Education